Margie H. Joyce, M. Ed. Learning & Design Strategist

email: margiej12@gmail.com tel: 202.251.0009 portfolio: http://www.margiejoyce.us

With over 15 years of experience working internationally, for small-businesses and large management consulting firms, I bring adaptability, insight and critical thinking to my work.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Learning & Design Strategist: April 2008 - Present

Sonjara Inc., Washington DC Metro Area

Provide leadership, project management and technical support in user interface design, visual design, and instructional design of web-based performance support tools for USAID and international development partners

- Collaborate across functional teams with partners, subject matter experts, data analysts and software developers
- Create detailed work plans, budgets and burn rate reports for technical work
- Gather requirements, analyze user needs and produced task workflows to identify the appropriate web strategies for client's goals and objectives
- Develop high-fidelity prototypes in HTML/CSS using responsive design
- Develop prototypes in Sketch and Adobe XD
- Write scripts and oversee user interface testing
- Provided visual design support to improve usability, navigation and overall user interface
- Provided end-user training for Sonjara content management system
- Provide instructional design and development of online tutorials, online learning modules and online communities of practice using Articulate StoryLine
- Experience using Agile for project management and Jira for task tracking

Senior Learning Strategist: August 2006 - March 2008

Booz Allen Hamilton, Learning and Development

- Developed creative courseware designs suitable for classroom, e-learning or blended learning.
- Collaborated with and provided guidance to curriculum advisors, internal clients and subject matter experts in the analysis of human performance and business needs.
- Wrote high level and detailed design documents mapping course objectives, learning activities, and evaluation to competencies and overall business needs.
- Provided educational consulting to assigned clients as appropriate.
- Oversaw video or audio recordings, editing, as well as digitization and archiving of learning objects.
- Researched and provided practical input toward the improvement of internal systems, processes and procedures that increased efficiency in managing, designing and delivering courseware.

Senior Program Officer/Project Manager: 2003 - 2006

Academy for Educational Development – Center for Applied Technology

- Managed several international education projects. Tasks included providing technical support in program design, developing scopes of work, writing sub-contract agreements, work breakdown structure, scheduling, budgeting, risk analysis planning, project logging and reporting.
- Oversaw the design, development and production of online learning including toolkits, online communities of practices, e-learning tutorials and courses in developing country context.
- Wrote concept papers, final reports and technical briefs on information communication technology and education.
- Specific projects included:
 - Provided technical assistance in instructional design to support the "Education Reform for the Knowledge Economy" (Erfke) Support Project in Jordan (USAID).
 - o Provided technical leadership in instructional design to produce an Environmental Studies "hard spots" CD-ROM and teachers implementation guide for primary schools in Jharkhand INDIA (USAID).
 - O Supervised and provided technical leadership for the USAID/dot-EDU Connectivity for Educator Development project in UGANDA which has established internet computer labs in 8 Primary Teacher Colleges. Manage a 15 person project team to oversee lab operations, digitize and enhance the national Primary Teachers College curriculum, develop and initiate sustainability strategies and ICT policy guidelines at College level, overall ICT policy at Ministry level and sound pedagogical inputs at teacher educator level.
 - o Provided technical assistance as part of a five person ICT-in-Education Assessment Team to write a national ICT options paper for the Ministry of Education, Science and Technology in (USAID/dot-EDU KENYA).
 - Conducted workshops and on-going support for teacher educators in Uganda and Jamaica taking the Harvard University online course: "Teaching to Standards with New Technologies."

Instructional Designer: June 2002 - 2003

Academy for Educational Development – Global Learning Portal

 Collaborated with team of programmers, content specialists, graphic artists to build conceptual framework of an international portal for teachers in developing countries (Received AED Technical Excellence Award for prototype design).

E-Learning Consultant: 2001 - 2003

AED/USAID/South Asia Regional Initiative for Energy (SARI/E) Training Program

 Directed the SARI/E project's New Delhi web design team and provided technical oversight to increase usability and improve interface design for the project web site. Managed the instructional design and development of four e-learning courses:
 Environmental Impact Assessments, Independent Regulation: Theory and Practice,
 Contract Design for Energy Trade, and Energy Efficiency.

IT Specialist: June 2001 – June 2002

Academy for Educational Development/ USAID/Learnlink Project

Responsible for re-designing, constructing, maintaining and updating the LearnLink website, and providing a full range of technical support services to all LearnLink field projects and core activities including: creating and maintaining the procurement database; managing the procurement of IT equipment for field projects; providing technical advice on the development of project web sites, CD-ROMs, electronic newsletters, on-line discussion forums, and other digital methods for communication and networking; researching and developing information and communication technology (ICT) tools.

Multimedia Lab Advisor/Web Consultant: September 2000 – July 2001 CIET (Computer Instruction Educational Technology) GEORGE MASON UNIVERSITY

Worked collaboratively with web team to re-design the Graduate School of Education (GSE) web site, including creating a new graphical identity and information architecture. Provided learner support in using computer applications such as MS Office, Adobe PhotoShop, and Macromedia Dreamweaver to GSE students and faculty. Responsible for troubleshooting technical issues with servers, hardware, and peripherals.

Contract Support Coordinator: June 2000 – September 2000 *MCI/WORLDCOM, McLean, VA*

 Provided technical and logistical support to outside vendors and United States Postal Service employees to insure the efficient installation of hardware necessary to implement the USPS nation-wide Intranet system.

Technical Support Agent: July 1999 – May 2000 STREAM INTERNATIONAL, Portland, OR

Provided professional and expedient technical support to end users of country's largest Cable Internet Service Provider including how to troubleshoot internet connectivity and use Windows 95, 98, NT and Macintosh OS, MS DOS, TCP/IP network components, ftp, IE and Netscape web browsers and e-mail clients, cable modems.

Project Coordinator/Writer/Editor: October 1997 – July 1999

LEARNING TECHNOLOGIES, TAIWAN, LTD., Taipei, Taiwan

 Coordinated the production of a bilingual (Mandarin/English) educational textbook, "Rockin' in America, Learning English through Music" created in video, audio and DVD format. Conducted needs assessment, market research and task breakdown analysis. Scheduled and participated in creative group meetings, interfaced with graphic designers and other outside vendors, oversaw written and visual production material. Created all English teaching material for a thrice-weekly Telephone English Course published in ALE (Actual Living English) News. Edited and wrote English teaching text for the various IN AMERICA publications targeted for Taiwanese market.

Public Relations/Publications Editor: March 1998 – July 1999

RITZ LANDIS HOTEL, Taipei, Taiwan

Designed and updated English section of bilingual (Mandarin/English) web site. Wrote and edited all the hotel's bilingual publications including: daily newsletters featuring hotel amenities and cultural sights in and around Taipei, brochures, bimonthly magazines, press-releases and press-kits, business correspondence for sales, marketing and public relations departments.

Title: EFL Teacher: January 1997 – December 1997

ELSI, Taipei, Taiwan

Taught basic, intermediate, and advanced English conversation and composition classes to K-12 students. Prepared teaching curriculum and provided direct instruction for intermediate and advanced English conversation and composition classes to various corporate accounts.

EDUCATION:

M.Ed. Instructional Design and Development, George Mason University; Fairfax, VA 4.0 GPA. (2001)

B.A. Liberal Arts; emphasis Linguistics, Minor in French/ESL Teaching Certificate, University of Montana, Missoula, MT 3.76 GPA (1994)

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT & CERTIFICATIONS:

Professional Development Training/Special Programs:

- Interaction Design Foundation UX course work, 2018
- "Teaching to Standards with New Technologies," Harvard University Online Course,
 2004
- "Managing Projects," ESI/George Washington University e-learning course, 2004
- "ICT for Development," USDA Online Course, 2002
- Chinese Language Program: Shandong University, Wei Hai, CHINA, 1996
- Study Abroad Program: Burgundy/Paris, FRANCE, 1994

Membership in Professional Societies: E-Learning Guild, Association for Advancement of Computing in Education (AACE), American Society for Training and Development (ASTD), Society for International Development (SID)

Countries of Work Experience:

Democratic Republic of Congo, Ghana, Jordan, Jamaica, Uganda, Kenya, Indonesia, India, Thailand, Jamaica, Taiwan